Kristian Martinez, Student

P. 954-826-6917

kristian.panku@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristian-martinez-40137b21b/https://github.com/Kristianmartinw Denver, Colorado

SKILLS F

React.js, JavaScript, jQuery, Redux, SQL, Git, Express, HTML5, CSS3

PROJECTS

Grandcypher Crew

https://grandcypher-crew.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/Kristianmartinw/grandcypher-crew

Grandcypher Crew is an app that allows a user to theory craft and formulate a party for the game Granblue Fantasy which primarily uses Python, Flask, and Javascript

- Implementation of Redux for storage of data allowed me to pull all the information I needed to display and made it more responsive for a better user experience.
- Media Querying allowed me to adjust my app to allow for more flexible sizing to account for different displays a user may be viewing the app from.
- Created flexible components that allowed me to reuse existing code for multiple pages, providing time efficient development.
- Extensive Conditional Rendering to allow users to use any features they are looking for with minimal input and also removal
 and additions of buttons to minimize user error.
- Community input for values on the characters and navigation to lead to a better user experience as well as providing an ample user base waiting for completion of the app, leading to a community-driven app.

Party Lure

https://party-lure.herokuapp.com/https://github.com/zanehamadi/Party-Lure

Party Lure is an app that allows users to connect and make groups with other players for a fictional game and primarily uses Python, Flask, and Javascript

- Implementation of AWS allowed for a more personal user experience to distinguish themselves from other users in the form of profile pictures..
- In depth forms bring an extensive user tailored experience that allows them more control on what they're looking for, leading to a more personalized user experience.
- Comprehensive search and filter querying implemented which gives the user full control over the data they're being given so they can quickly access the information they want.

GoodGamez

https://good-gamez.herokuapp.com/games https://github.com/penced0513/goodgamez

GoodGamez is a Goodreads clone that allows a user to browse a library of games and assign them to shelves of preset or custom categories. It uses Javascript and Express.

- Pug forms were made to allow for a user-first mentality, provided in the form of page flow and reactivity of the app navigation.
- Javascript was used to query for the categories of games on the home page which lets users dive straight into the action and give them a taste of what to expect.
- Reactive comments allows a user to share their opinion of a game in real time and gives a greater sense of community by allowing others to view them and interact.
- Ratings are implemented to allow users to assess their interest in a listed game and quickly filter out what is worthy of their time, giving them more control of their time on the app.

Houndcloud

https://hound-cloud.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/Kristianmartinw/houndcloud

Houndcloud is a Soundcloud clone that allows a user to post their own files of dogs barking listed under different breeds instead of music. It consists of Javascript and Express.

- Utilized AWS to allow for high volume storage of user-uploaded files allowing for a quicker and snappier navigation experience.
- A music player library was added on the footer to allow a user to control the sound files they are playing from any page and keep them engaged.
- Conditional rendering on the profile page allows a user quick access to features that they would want with minimal need for

navigation through different pages.

EXPERIENCE

Librarian

Broward College, Nov 2014 - Feb 2015

- Queried through the library database to quickly and efficiently find books students were searching for and giving them the location of where it could be found.
- Usage of the Dewey Decimal system for classification and storage of the books on the shelves throughout the multiple story library.
- Constantly learned knowledge on different subjects to provide students with recommendations on similar books they were looking for in case the specific one they wanted was checked out.
- Worked with other libraries to order books to be sent to us if a user required a specific book.

Literary Editor

Broward College Magazine, 2014 - 2016

- Worked with a team of individuals to design the layout of the magazine as well as the choice of submissions that would be added to the magazine.
- Constantly worked to meet deadlines while in a high paced environment and adjusting to any revisions needing to be made through last minute high stress crunch times.
- Worked hand in hand with the students that submitted their works to provide a better overall piece for the magazine, offering input as well as taking into account their vision.

Transportation Security Officer

Denver International Airport, Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

- Maintaining focus and awareness while working in a stressful environment which includes noise from alarms, machinery and people, crowd distractions, time pressure, and disruptive and angry passengers.
- Engaging in continuous development of critical thinking skills, necessary to mitigate actual and potential security threats, by identifying, evaluating, and applying appropriate situational options and approaches with minimal direction.
- Retaining and implementing knowledge of all applicable Standard Operating Procedures, demonstrating responsible and dependable behavior, while also being open to change and adapting to new information or unexpected obstacles.

EDUCATION

App Academy - Immersive software development course with focus on full stack web development (Spring 2021)